var data = [
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Define chemistry",answer:"The science of composition, structure, properties and reactions of matter"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"List the five main braches of chemistry",answer:
  ['organic chemistry','inorganic chemistry','physical chemistry','analytic chemistry','biochemistry'
  ]
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is organic chemistry",answer:"comes from living organisms, is the study of compounds that contain carbon"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"what is inorganic chemistry",answer:"Anything related none living matter"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"what is biochemistry",answer:"The study of chemistry of living system"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is vital force theory",answer:"In the early 19th century Jons Jacob Berzelius developed it"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What does vital force theory state",answer:"organic compounds cannot be made in the lab from inorganic"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"When was vital force rejected",answer:"1820"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Who disproved vital force theory",answer:"Friedrich Wohler"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"What is Urea", answer: "Is the first organic compound prepared in lab"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"Where are Urea found ", answer:"Animal urine from organic compound"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"Write the preparation equation of Urea", answer:" Ag CNO + NH4Cl Ag Cl => NH4CNO"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:" Write the equation of Urea", answer:"NH2CONH2"
    
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"What is organic compound", answer:"Covalent bonded compound containing carbon excluding carbonates and oxides"
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"What are the common sources of organic compound", answer:  [
    'plants and animals',
    ' petroleum and natural gases',
    'coal',
    ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"What are Classification of Carbon", answer:
  [
    {'primary carbon': "carbon atom attached to none or other carbon"
      
    },
    {'secondary carbon': "carbon atom attached to two other carbons"
      
    },
    {'tertiary carbon': "carbon atom attached to three other carbons"
      
    },
    {'quaternary carbon': "carbon atom attached to four other carbons"
      
    },
    ],
    
  },
  
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"why carbon is a unique element", answer:"carbon has a valance of four means tetra valance','it has ability to form strong covalent bond','carbon may form single bond, double bond and even triple bond','it has catenation property"
  },
  {sub:"Chem" , question:"what is catenation", answer:"Is the ability of carbon atom link with other carbon atom form long chain or large ring"
    
  },
  
  { sub:"Chem", question:"Define hydrocarbons",answer:"Are compounds that contain carbon and hydrogen only"
  },
  { sub:"Chem", question:"List at least three common uses of hydrocarbons", answer:[
	  "Fuels",
	  "candle wax",
	  "gasoline",

  ]
  },
  { sub:"Chem",question:"List at least three hydrocarbon compounds", answer: [
	  'methane',
	  'propene',
	  'pentyne',
  ]
  },
  { sub:"Chem" , question:"Differentiate between saturated and unsaturated hydrocarbons",answer:[
	  {'Saturated':" are hydrocarbons that contain only c-c single bonds"
	  },
	  {'Un-saturated':" are hydrocarbons that contain c-c multiple bonds(double or triple bonds)"
	  }
  ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the most common classification of hydrocarbons",answer:[
	  'Aliphatic hydrocarbons',
	  'Aromatic hydrocarbons'
  ]
  },
  { sub:"Chem" , question:"How does a branched hydrocarbon differ from a normal hydrocarbon",answer:"Because the surface area of alkane decreases with branching."
  },
  { sub:"Chem",question:"Without referring to a table, predict which has higher boiling point between hexane and octane Explain your answer", answer:"Octane, because of increasing number of carbon and molecular mass"
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Name the most important reaction of alkane",answer:"Combustion",
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"If 25ml of hexane were added to 200ml of water in a beaker, which of the following would you expect to happen",answer:"Hexane would not dissolve in the water and would float on the top."
  },
  { sub:"Chem",question:"Define Alkenes",answer:"Alkenes- are unsaturated hydrocarbons containing at least one carbon-–carbon double bond between carbon atoms"

  },
  { sub:"Chem",question:"State classification of Alkenes",answer:"Symmetrical Alkenes,Asymmetrical Alkenes"

  },
  { sub:"Chem",question:"Differentiate between Symmetrical and Asymmetrical Alkenes",answer:[
	  {'Symmetrical alkenes':" are alkenes in which two same groups are being attached to the carbon-carbon double bond."
	  },
	  {'Asymmetrical Alkenes':"are alkenes in which two different groups are being attached to carbon-carbon double bonds."
	  },
	  

  ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Define functional group",answer:"Is an atom or a group of atom within a molecule that give a certain characteristic to the organic compounds",

  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"",answer:""                                                                               },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Generally, an organic compound is composed of two parts, Name each",answer:[
	  "• Hydrocarbon part",
	  "Active part or functional group"
  ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Define Alcohols",answer:"Alcohols- are organic compounds which contain hydroxyl group (-OH) as functional group"

  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the general formula of Alcohol",answer:"R-OH (Hydroxyl group)" 

  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the general formula of ethers",answer:"The general formula of ether is R-O-R" 
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Differentiate between Aldehyde and ketone",answer:[
	  {'Aldehyde':"is organic compound which contain aldehydic carbonyl group at the side."
	  },
	  {'Ketone':"is organic compound which contain carbonyl group at the middle"
	  },

  ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the general formula of Aldehyde",answer:"RCHO"                                                                              
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the general formula of Ketone",answer:"R-CO-R"                                                                              
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"Define carboxylic acid",answer:"Carboxylic acid is an organic compound that contain carboxyl group as functional."
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the general formula of carboxylic acid",answer:"RCOOH"                                                                              
  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"Define bimolecules",answer:"The chemical constituents of the living system are called biomolecules."                     
  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"What are the major types of biomolecules",answer:[
	  'Carbohydrates',
	  'Proteins',
	  'Lipids',
	  'Nucleic acids',
  ]
  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"What are the fields’ of biochemistry",answer:[
	  'Structural biology',
	  'Enzymology',
	  'Metabolism',

  ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What are carbohydrates",answer:[
	  'Are polyhydorxy aldehyde or ketone.',
	  'Are most abundant organic compounds in nature',
  ]
  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"What is the general formula of carbohydrates",answer:"Cx(H2O)Y"                      
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"What foods are found in glucose and fructose",answer:[
	  {'Glucose': "found in the blood"},
	  {'Fructose' :"found in fruits"},

  ]
  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"How many types are classified into carbohydrates, on basis of the behavior of hydrolysis",answer:[
	  "Monosaccharides",
	  "Oligosaccharides",
	  "Polysaccharies",
  ]
  },
  {sub:"Chem",question:"On basis of taste, how many are classified into carbohydrates",answer:[
	  'Sugar',
	  'Non-sugar',

  ]
  },                                                      {sub:"Chem",question:"Differentiate between essential and non-essential amino acids",answer:[
	  {'Essential amino acids':[
		  "Arginine",
		  "Lysine",
		  "Histidine",
		  "Methionine",
		  "Isoleucine",
		  "Threonine",
		  "Leucine",
		  "Phenylalanine",
		  "Valine",
		  "Tryptophan.",
	  ]
	  },
	  {'Non-essential amino acids':[
		  "Alanine",
		  "Glycine",
		  "Asparagine",
		  "Proline",
		  "Aspartate",
		  "Serine",
		  "Glutamate",
		  "Cysteine",
		  "Glumamine",
		  "Tyrosine.",

	  ]
	  },
  ]
  },
  
]

export default data
